We've added in
controls for our player, so
then that way we can
move them up if we press
the up key or backwards
if we press the down key.
If we press the left or right arrow keys,
you can see that we rotate around our scene.
So now what we want to do is we actually
want to push the player in the direction that
the camera's facing,
so for example, if we're
facing this way, we want our player
to go directly up in our game view.
Now an interesting to note is this
button in the top left for global or local.
You can see when I change it, the
positions of those arrows actually change.
So currently you can
see actually what is
the y direction of our
ball as it's rotating.
If we take a look at our focal point, we
can actually see which way is currently the
front of our focal point, the
direction that our camera's facing.
So if we rotate our
camera and we watch these
axes, you can actually
see the z axis pointing
in the direction that
our camera is pointing.
So you can see our camera,
there's the direction in our game.
As we rotate, you can
actually see that the
camera is following
those local coordinates.
Now it's helpful to use local
coordinates in a case like this.
When you're actually
trying to set up your
scene and set up your
environment and you want
everything to be in the
same place, using something
like our global coordinate
system is a lot better.
So then that way you can make sure that
when you're changing the positions of things
or you're changing
the rotation or anything
like that, you can always
make sure that when
you drag these arrows,
it doesn't drag it off.
For example, if I change this to local and
I rotate the y, when I drag the z, it's not
actually going directly forward
on the z, it's going at an angle.
So we'll reset all of that.
So using global and using local
are helpful for different situations.
So in our player controller
class, what we're actually
going to do is get a
reference to our focal point.
So that way we can know when the focal point
is facing in a certain direction, we will
move that player in
the direction it's facing.
So we'll create a new private
since our focal point is a game object.
We need a game object variable
and we'll just call this the focal point.
So we avoid confusion.
In our start method, we want to
get a reference to that focal point.
So we'll get our focal point
variable and we'll set it.
Now in this case,
because our game object is
in the scene, we can
use game object.find.
So this will find that game
object in the project hierarchy.
And we can actually just use the name.
So we called it focal point
with capital P and F and spaces.
So now we have a
reference to that focal point.
So now instead of
moving the player in the
forward direction of
our world, we'll actually
make it the forward direction
that our camera is pointing in.
So if we use our focal point and we get its
current transform and we get the forward
direction that it's facing, now if we go
into Unity, when we press play on the editor,
you can see that I can still
move forward or backwards.
But then if I rotate the
camera, say 90 degrees,
now when I move forward,
it goes in that direction.
And when I go backwards, it
goes in the opposite direction.
So now we can actually
use our camera to be
able to control how our
ball moves in the scene.
So what you're going
to do is you're going
to add your own private game
object variable for the focal point.
When you're start
method, you're going to get
a reference to the
focal point in our project
hierarchy and set that
to our own variable.
And then in our update
method, instead of
using the vector 3 dot
forward, you're actually
going to use the forward
direction of our focal point.
Now it's your turn.